A Guide to the Warren Weaver papers FA419
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Sloan Kettering Institute, 1959-1973; 7; 0.8 Cubic Feet
  - Minutes: Sloan-Kettering Institute: Board of Trustees, 1967 (Box 36, Folder 340)
  - Minutes: Sloan-Kettering Institute, 1966-1967 (Box 36, Folder 341)
  - Finances, 1966-1967 (Box 36, Folder 342)
- General Files, 1932-1979; 8; 3.5 Cubic Feet
  The General Files contain correspondence arranged alphabetically by subject or name of correspondent. The majority of the material presented in Series 8 relates to Weaver's personal writings, books and articles.
  - General, 1964-1967 (Box 36, Folder 343)
  - Addresses and Phone Numbers (Box 36, Folder 344)
  - American Academy of Arts & Sciences: Business, 1964-1966 (Box 36, Folder 345)
  - American Academy of Arts & Sciences: Committee, 1965-1967 (Box 36, Folder 346)
  - American Academy of Arts & Sciences: Voss, John, 1965-1968 (Box 36, Folder 347)
  - Andrews, Emerson F., 1964-1966 (Box 36, Folder 348)
  - Astronomy and Space, 1949-1963 (Box 36, Folder 349)
  - AT&T Show, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 350)
  - The Attractiveness of Dessert, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 351)
  - Basic Research, 1959 (Box 37, Folder 352)
  - Biology and Biochemistry, 1945-1965 (Box 37, Folder 353)
  - Biology in Human Affairs, 1974 (Box 37, Folder 354)
  - Bronowski, Jacob, 1962-1975 (Box 37, Folder 355)
  - Bronowski, Jacob: Extracts from the Identity of Man (Box 37, Folder 356)
  - Business and Royalty Reports, 1970-1972 (Box 37, Folder 357)
  - Careers in Science (published in 1965) (Box 38, Folder 358)
  - Century Club, 1963-1973 (Box 38, Folder 359)
  - Citations, 1952-1971 (Box 38, Folder 360)
  - Collaborators, 1964-1971 (Box 38, Folder 361)
  - Communication: Speech, Words, 1953 (Box 38, Folder 362)
  - Communication Theory, 1949-1956 (Box 38, Folder 363)
  - Computers, Information (Box 38, Folder 364)
  - Criticisms, 1964-1966 (Box 38, Folder 365)
  - Equipment: Indoors (Box 38, Folder 366)
  - Equipment: Outdoors (Box 38, Folder 367)
  - Food, Population, Energy, 1953-1961 (Box 38, Folder 368)
  - Fosdick, Raymond B., 1965 (Box 38, Folder 369)
  - Geology, 1957-1969 (Box 38, Folder 370)
  - Harper and Row, 1966-1973 (Box 38, Folder 371)
  - Harrar and Rockefeller Foundation, 1962-1966 (Box 39, Folder 372)
  - Insurance: Rockefeller Foundation & Sloan Foundation (Box 39, Folder 373)
  - Lady Luck: Correspondence, 1963-1976 (Box 39, Folder 374)
  - Math, Games, Puzzles (Box 39, Folder 375)
  - Math, Nature of Proof, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 376)
  - Medical Education (Box 39, Folder 377)
  - Miscellaneous, 1944-1978 (Box 39, Folder 378)
  - Molecular Biology, 1949-1972 (Box 40, Folder 379)
  - Mouse Cartoon, 1956 (Box 40, Folder 380)
  - Mouse Cartoon, 1956 (Box 40, Folder 381)
  - Mouse Cartoon, 1956 (Box 40, Folder 382)
  - Mouse Cartoon, 1956 (Box 40, Folder 383)
  - Mouse Cartoon, 1956 (Box 40, Folder 384)
  - Oral History (Columbia University), 1961-1965 (Box 40, Folder 385)
  - Origin of the Elements, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 386)
  - Philanthropy Book: Letters, 1967-1968 (Box 40, Folder 387)
  - Philanthropy Book: Reviews, 1967-1968 (Box 40, Folder 388)
  - Philosophical Society Committee, 1963-1964 (Box 40, Folder 389)
  - Philosophy of Science, 1965-1966 (Box 40, Folder 390)
  - Physics, 1948-1963 (Box 40, Folder 391)
  - Priorities in Science, 1964-1969 (Box 41, Folder 392)
  - Probability Research, 1938-1956 (Box 41, Folder 393)
  - Publications (Box 41, Folder 394)
  - Publications (Box 41, Folder 395)
  - Public Understanding of Science, 1959-1973 (Box 42, Folder 396)
  - Real Estate Tax, 1959 (Box 42, Folder 397)
    Permanently Restricted - Confidential Material ? Financial
  - Reprint Information, 1967-1969 (Box 42, Folder 398)
  - Reprint List (Box 42, Folder 399)
  - Reprint List (Box 42, Folder 400)
    Permanently Restricted - Confidential Material ? Personnel
  - Rice (International Rice Research Institute), 1962-1973 (Box 42, Folder 401)
  - Rockefeller Foundation: Pre-World War II, Chapter 6, 1961-1968 (Box 42, Folder 402)
  - Science, 1966-1967 (Box 42, Folder 403)
  - Science: Research and Writings, 1950-1971 (Box 42, Folder 404)
  - Science and Imagination: Basic Books (Box 42, Folder 405)
  - Science and Imagination: Basic Books: Letters, 1967-1968 (Box 42, Folder 406)
  - Science and Imagination: Basic Books: Lynch, 1967 (Box 42, Folder 407)
  - Science and Imagination: Basic Books: Reviews, 1967-1968 (Box 42, Folder 408)
  - Science and Imagination: Basic Books: Rosenthal, 1965-1968 (Box 42, Folder 409)
  - Science and Imagination: Basic Books: Royalties, 1967-1969 (Box 42, Folder 410)
  - Science and Government, 1959-1978 (Box 42, Folder 411)
  - Science and Religion, 1946-1968 (Box 43, Folder 412)
  - Science and War, 1961-1980 (Box 43, Folder 413)
  - Scribner Book: Letters, 1966-1967 (Box 43, Folder 414)
  - Scribner Book: Memoirs, RF Diary, 1932-1952 (Box 43, Folder 415)
  - Scribner Book: Scene of Change, 1969-1971 (Box 43, Folder 416)
  - Shilen, Ronald, 1963-1965 (Box 43, Folder 417)
  - Space Program, 1949-1954 (Box 43, Folder 418)
  - Two Cultures (C.P. Snow), 1959-1964 (Box 43, Folder 419)
  - Units: Conversion Table, Basic Data (Box 43, Folder 420)
  - Watergate, 1974 (Box 43, Folder 421)
  - Willis, Ann Deming, 1966 (Box 43, Folder 422)
  - Women and Science, 1975 (Box 43, Folder 423)
- Speeches and Articles, 1937-1966; 9; 1 Cubic Feet
  Contains speeches, articles, notes and speech cards maintained together as received by RAC. Weaver's speech cards, loosely arranged chronologically by year (1939-1966), are a set of handwritten index cards presumably used as prompts during his presentations and addresses.
  - Material for Speeches and Articles (Box 44, Folder 424)
  - Speeches or Articles Not Published (Box 44, Folder 425)
  - Manuscripts of Speeches and Articles Published (Box 44, Folder 426)
  - Speeches: General (Box 44, Folder 427)
  - Speeches: Mary Andrews College of First Aid (Box 44, Folder 428)
  - Speeches: Education (Box 44, Folder 429)
  - Speeches: Introductory Information (Box 44, Folder 430)
  - Speeches: Radiation, Defense, Security, 1947-1957 (Box 44, Folder 431)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Program Trips, 1937-1959 (Box 44, Folder 432)
  - Speeches: Cards, 1939-1954 (Box 44, Folder 433)
  - Speeches: Cards, 1954-1955 (Box 44, Folder 434)
  - Speeches: Cards, 1956-1957 (Box 44, Folder 435)
  - Speeches: Cards, 1958-1961 (Box 45, Folder 436)
  - Speeches: Cards, 1961-1964 (Box 45, Folder 437)
  - Speeches: Cards, 1961-1964 (Box 45, Folder 438)
  - Speeches: Cards, 1964-1966 (Box 45, Folder 439)
  - Speeches: Cards, undated (Box 46, Folder 440)
- Awards, Citations and Degrees, 1936-1969; 10; 2 Cubic Feet
  Series 10 Awards, Citations and Degrees contains documentation of a selection of the honors Weaver received including most notably the Public Welfare Medal from the National Academy of Sciences (1957), the first Arches of Science Award from the Pacific Science Center (1965), the UNESCO Kalinga Prize (1965) and the citation for the Medal for Merit from the United States.
  - Honors, 1948-1965 (Box 46, Folder 441)
  - Arches of Science: Notification and Press Conference, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 442)
  - Arches of Science: Press Clippings, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 443)
  - Arches of Science: Ceremony, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 444)
  - Arches of Science: Tributes and Telegrams, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 445)
  - Arches of Science: Congratulatory Letters and Telegrams, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 446)
  - Arches of Science: Photographs, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 447)
  - Arches of Science: Recipient, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 448)
  - Arches of Science, 1966 (Box 46, Folder 449)
  - National Academy of Sciences: Congratulations, 1969 (Box 47, Folder 450)
  - Notes of Appreciation, 1958-1967 (Box 47, Folder 451)
  - UNESCO: Kalinga Prize, 1965-1967 (Box 47, Folder 452)
  - UNESCO: Kalinga Prize: News Clippings, 1965-1966 (Box 47, Folder 453)
  - UNESCO (Box 47, Folder 454)
  - Christian Michelsons Institute: Correspondence Membership, Bergen, Norway, 1936 January 21 (Box 48)
  - Scientific American, 1945 August 28 (Box 48)
  - Department of the Navy: Appreciation for Service as a Member of the Naval Research Advisory Committee, 1946-1947 (Box 48)
  - National Medal of Merit Citation, 1948 January 2 (Box 48)
  - University of Sao Paolo, Brazil (Sc.D.), 1956-1959 (Box 48)
  - Adventures in Science Audio Recording: Warren Weaver and Dean Rusk, 1953 January 6 (Box 48)
    Conditions Governing Access
    RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media and original digital media. In addition separated media may not yet have undergone stabilization procedures. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
  - American Philosophical Society: Membership Certificate, 1954 April 21 (Box 48)
  - Clipper Club: Membership Certificate, 1955 April 21 (Box 48)
  - Invitation to the Inauguration of U.S. President Dwight D. Eisenhower, 1957 (Box 48)
  - National Academy of Sciences Public Welfare Medal: Press Release, 1957 (Box 48)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, Fellow, 1958 May 14 (Box 48)
  - Rockefeller Foundation: Identification Card, 1958-1961 (Box 48)
  - National Association of Science Writers: Honorary Member, 1959 (Box 48)
  - National Science Foundation: Appointment to the National Science Board (term ending 1960 May 10) (Box 48)
  - New York University Courant Institute of Medical Sciences: Remarks on the Occasion of the $2,750 grant, 1961 October 20 (Box 48)
  - Drexel University of Technology: Doctor of Science Degree (Honorary), 1961 December 5 (Box 48)
  - Southern Research Institute: Honorary Member of Advisory Council, 1962 (Box 48)
  - RPI: Doctor of Engineering (D.E.), 1962 June 8 (Box 48)
  - University of Rochester (I.H.D.), 1963 (Box 48)
  - New York Academy of Sciences: Membership Certificate, 1963 September 20 (Box 48)
  - University of Pittsburgh: Doctor of Science Degree (Honorary), 1964 June 1 (Box 48)
  - New York University: Doctor of Science (Honorary), 1964 June 10 (Box 48)
  - New York Academy of Sciences: Fellow, 1964 December 2 (Box 48)
  - New York Times Obituaries, 1966 July 20 (Box 48)
  - Alfred P. Sloan Foundation: Tribute, 1967 July 17 (Box 48)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science: 50 Year Member Certificate, 1968 October 29 (Box 48)
  - Salk Institute for Biological Studies: Trustee Emeritus Resolution, 1968 December 19 (Box 48)
  - National Academy of Sciences: Membership Certificate, 1969 April 29 (Box 48)
  - Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center: On the Occasion of Resignation (Box 48)
- Manuscripts, 1963-1965; 11; 2 Cubic Feet
  Series 11 Manuscripts and Series 12 Reprints document Weaver's writings, articles, collaborations and publications including Lady Luck: The Theory of Probability (1963) and U.S. Philanthropic Foundations: Their History, Structure, Management and Record (1967).
  - Lady Luck Manuscript (with written edits and revisions) (Box 49, Folder 455)
  - Lady Luck Manuscript (typed) (Box 49, Folder 456)
  - Lady Luck Illustrations (Box 50, Folder 456.1)
    CLOSED to research due to preservation concerns
  - Foundations: Manuscript Part I (Box 49, Folder 457)
  - Foundations: Manuscript Part II (Box 49, Folder 458)
  - Foundations: Manuscript Part II (Box 49, Folder 459)
  - Foundations: Manuscript Part II Outdated Material (Box 51, Folder 460)
  - Foundations: Collaboration Accepted (Box 51, Folder 461)
  - Foundations: Collaboration (Box 51, Folder 462)
  - Foundations: Collaboration (Box 51, Folder 463)
  - Foundations: Collaboration (Box 51, Folder 464)
  - Foundations: Collaboration (Box 51, Folder 465)
  - Foundations: Collaboration Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 52, Folder 466)
  - Foundations: Collaboration Correspondence, 1965 (Box 52, Folder 467)
  - Foundations: Collaboration Declined (Box 52, Folder 468)
  - Drafts of Essays, 1965 (Box 52, Folder 469)
- Reprints, 1920-1987; 1933-1977; 12; 6 Cubic Feet
  Series 11 Manuscripts and Series 12 Reprints document Weaver's writings, articles, collaborations and publications including Lady Luck: The Theory of Probability (1963) and U.S. Philanthropic Foundations: Their History, Structure, Management and Record (1967). The contents include, but are not limited to those works listed in the reprints indexes.
  The reprints are arranged into two subseries containing works written by Warren Weaver, and works written by other scholars and academicians that were collected by Weaver. Each subseries is loosely arranged chronologically.
  - Works by Warren Weaver, 1
    - Works by Warren Weaver, 1920-1927 (Box 52, Folder 470)
      - Physical Review: The Pressure of Sound, 1920 May (Box 52, Folder 470)
      - The American Mathematical Monthly: Forecast, 1920 May (Box 52, Folder 470)
      - The American Mathematical Monthly: The Average Reading Vocabulary: An Application of Bayes' Theorem, 1920 October (Box 52, Folder 470)
      - The Physical Review: The Kinetic Theory of Magnetism, 1920 November (Box 52, Folder 470)
      - The Physical Review (WW with Max Mason): The Settling of Small Particles in a Fluid, 1924 March (Box 52, Folder 470)
      - The Physical Review: The Duration of the Transient State in the Settling of Small Particles, 1926 April (Box 52, Folder 470)
      - Zetschrift Fur Phyisik: Die Diffusion kleiner Teilchen in einer Flussigkeit (The Diffusion of Small Particles in a Fluid), 1927 (Box 52, Folder 470)
    - Works by Warren Weaver, 1928-1929 (Box 52, Folder 471)
      - The Physical Review (WW with H.W. March): Diffusion Problem for a Solid in Contact with a Stirred Liquid, 1928 June (Box 52, Folder 471)
      - Zetschrift Fur Phyisik: Die Sedimentationszeit kleiner Teilchen in einer Flussigkeit (The Sedimentation of Small Particles in a Fluid), 1928 (Box 52, Folder 471)
      - The American Mathematical Monthly: A Debate on the Theory of Relativity, 1929 January (Box 52, Folder 471)
      - The Scientific Monthly: Science and Imagination, 1929 November (Box 52, Folder 471)
    - Works by Warren Weaver, 1930-1931 (Box 52, Folder 472)
      - The American Mathematical Monthly: Mathematics and the Problem of Ore Location, 1962 (Box 52, Folder 472)
      - Bulletin of the Associated State Engineering Societies: Geophysical Prospecting, 1930 July (Box 52, Folder 472)
      - The Scientific Monthly: The Reign of Probability, 1930 November (Box 52, Folder 472)
      - Recent Trends in American College Education (Proceedings of the Institute for Administrative Officers of Higher Education): The New Curriculum at the University of Wisconsin, 1931 (Box 52, Folder 472)
    - Works by Warren Weaver, 1932 (Box 53, Folder 473)
      - Journal of Mathematics and Physics: Uplift Pressure on Dams, 1932 June (Box 53, Folder 473)
      - The American Mathematical Monthly: Conformal Representation with Applications to Problems of Applied Mathematics, 1932 October (Box 53, Folder 473)
    - Works by Warren Weaver, 1937-1946 (Box 53, Folder 474)
      - The American Mathematical Monthly: Review: Mathematics of Modern Engineering, 1937 January (Box 53, Folder 474)
      - The American Mathematical Monthly: Lewis Carrol and a Geometrical Paradox, 1938 April (Box 53, Folder 474)
      - Lewis Carrol: Correspondence Numbers, 1966-1968 (Box 53, Folder 474)
      - The Riverside Church: A Scientist's Prayer, 1942 February 1 (Box 53, Folder 474)
      - Applied Mathematics Panel, National Defense Research Committee, The: Estimation of Balloon Barrage Probabilities and Similar Problems, 1943 May 14 (Box 53, Folder 474)
      - Society for Freedom in Sciences: Free Science, 1945 November (Box 53, Folder 474)
      - Address delivered at Quarterly Sales Committee Dinner, United State Rubber Company: Science, 1946 December 10 (Box 53, Folder 474)
    - Works by Warren Weaver, 1944-1948 (Box 53, Folder 474A)
      Restricted from research - Classified.
    - Works by Warren Weaver, 1948 (Box 53, Folder 475)
      - Reviews of Modern Physics: Statistical Freedom of the Will, 1948 January (Box 53, Folder 475)
      - American Scientist: Science and Complexity, 1963 (Box 53, Folder 475)
      - The Atlantic Monthly: Size, 1948 September (Box 53, Folder 475)
      - The Scientific Monthly: Probability, Rarity, Interest and Surprise, 1948 December (Box 53, Folder 475)
    - Works by Warren Weaver, 1949 (Box 53, Folder 476)
      - Translation, 1949 July 15 (Box 53, Folder 476)
      - Scientific American: The Mathematics of Communication, 1949 July (Box 53, Folder 476)
      - Population and Food, 1949 (Box 53, Folder 476)
    - Works by Warren Weaver, 1950-1951 (Box 53, Folder 477)
      - Scientific Monthly: Reply to McConnell's letter re Extrasensory Perception, 1950 February (Box 53, Folder 477)
      - Scientific American: Probability, 1950 October (Box 53, Folder 477)
      - Science: Questions for the September Conference, 1951 August 31 (Box 53, Folder 477)
      - The Princeton University Library Chronicle: Alice's Adventures in Wonderland: Its Origin and Its Author, 1951 Autumn (Box 53, Folder 477)
      - New York Herald Tribune Annual Forum: A Community Tries to Be Sensible, 1951 October 23 (Box 53, Folder 477)
      - American Academy of Arts and Sciences: Report on Arden House Meeting, 1951 November 2 (Box 53, Folder 477)
      - The Scientific Monthly: Protein Structure Studies, 1951 December (Box 53, Folder 477)
      - Statement for the Advisory Committee for Agricultural Activities (consisting of Stakman, Bradfield and Mangelsdorf, with collaboration from Weaver, Harrar and Miller): The World Food Problem, Agriculture and the Rockefeller Foundation, 1951 (Box 53, Folder 477)
    - Works by Warren Weaver, 1952-1954 (Box 54, Folder 478)
      - Scientific American: Statistics, 1952 January (Box 54, Folder 478)
      - ed. Lyman Bryson, Harper and Brothers Publishers: Facing the Future's Risks (Probability and Statistics), 1952 (Box 54, Folder 478)
      - A Review of the General Semantics: Recent Contributions to the Mathematical Theory of Communication, 1953 Summer (Box 54, Folder 478)
      - Scientific American: Fundamental Questions in Science, 1953 September (Box 54, Folder 478)
      - Science: Who Speaks for Whom or for What? (Editorial), 1954 February 26 (Box 54, Folder 478)
      - The Scientific Monthly: People, Energy, and Food, 1954 June (Box 54, Folder 478)
      - Proceedings of The American Philosophical Society: The Mathematical Manuscripts of Lewis Carroll, 1954 October 15 (Box 54, Folder 478)
      - Saturday Review: Peace of Mind, 1954 December 11 (Box 54, Folder 478)
      - Introduction to Dr. Edward U. Condon of Berkeley, CA at the Annual Meeting of the American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1954 (Box 54, Folder 478)
    - Works by Warren Weaver, 1955 (Box 54, Folder 479)
      - Look: Can a Scientist Believe in God?, 1955 April 5 (Box 54, Folder 479)
      - Commencement Address, Scardsdale High School, Scarsdale, NY: What's Past is Prologue, 1955 June 24 (Box 54, Folder 479)
      - The Journal of the Patent Office Society: The Patent Office Problem, 1955 September (Box 54, Folder 479)
      - Science: Science and People, 1955 December (Box 54, Folder 479)
      - Machine Translation of Languages, Locke and Booth, ed. MIT: Foreword, The New Tower, 1955 (Box 54, Folder 479)
      - American Documentation: The Patent Office Problem, 1955 (Box 54, Folder 479)
    - Works by Warren Weaver, 1956 (Box 54, Folder 480)
      - Scientific American: Lewis Carrol: Mathematician, 1956 April (Box 54, Folder 480)
      - U.S. News and World Report: What You Should Know About Danger from X Rays, 1956 June 29 (Box 54, Folder 480)
      - Challenge: How Radiation Can Affect Our Children (Interview with WW), 1956 October (Box 54, Folder 480)
      - Pasadena Revisited, 1956 November 15 (Box 54, Folder 480)
      - The Princeton University Library Chronicle: The Parish Collection of Carrolliana, 1956 Winter (Box 54, Folder 480)
      - National Academy of Sciences, National Research Council: Report of the Committee on Genetic Effects of Atomic Radiation (WW Chairman & Author), 1956 (Box 54, Folder 480)
    - Works by Warren Weaver, 1957 (Box 54, Folder 481)
      - Hearings before a Subcommittee of the Committee on Foreign Relations, U.S. Senate, 84th Congress: Control and Reduction of Armaments, 1957 January 16-17 (Box 54, Folder 481)
      - Medical Research Planning Conference (Address): Operations Research, 1957 April 25-27 (Box 54, Folder 481)
      - Journal of the Franklin Institute: Radiations and the Genetic Threat, 1957 April (Box 54, Folder 481)
      - Public Health Reports: New Dimensions of Learning in a Free Society, 1957 November (Box 54, Folder 481)
      - Look: Christmas 1957, 1957 December 24 (Box 54, Folder 481)
      - Bulletin of Atomic Scientists: Science and the Citizen, 1957 December (Box 54, Folder 481)
    - Works by Warren Weaver, 1958 (Box 54, Folder 482)
      - Hearings before a Subcommittee of the Committee on Government Operations, 85th Congress:, 1958 January 20-22 (Box 54, Folder 482)
      - Science: Communicative Accuracy, 1958 March 7 (Box 54, Folder 482)
      - Science: How Big is Too Big?, 1958 July 18 (Box 54, Folder 482)
      - The Rockefeller Foundation (Report for): Ave Atque Vale, 1958 August (Box 54, Folder 482)
      - Scientific American: The Encouragement of Science, 1958 September (Box 54, Folder 482)
      - Rockefeller Foundation Annual Report: A Quarter Century in the Natural Sciences, 1958 (Box 54, Folder 482)
    - Works by Warren Weaver, 1959 (Box 55, Folder 483)
      - Saturday Review: A Scientist Ponders Faith, 1959 January 3 (Box 55, Folder 483)
      - Air Force: A Scientist Ponders Faith, 1959 March (Box 55, Folder 483)
      - Science: Dither, 1959 August 7 (Box 55, Folder 483)
      - Scence: Report of the Special Committee, 1959 November 20 (Box 55, Folder 483)
      - Proceedings of the Robert A. Welch Foundation Conferences on Chemical Research: Science and the World of Scholarship, 1959 November 16-18 (Box 55, Folder 483)
      - Atlantico: Reflexiones De Un Hombre De Ciencia Sobre La Fe (A Scientist Ponders Faith), 1959 (Box 55, Folder 483)
    - Works by Warren Weaver, 1960 (Box 55, Folder 484-486)
      - Science: The Moment of Truth, 1960 January 29 (Box 55, Folder 484-486)
      - The Robert A. Welch Foundation Research Bulletin: Science and the World of Scholarship, 1960 January (Box 55, Folder 484-486)
      - Saturday Review: The Case of the Wayword Words, 1960 March 5 (Box 55, Folder 484-486)
      - The New York Public Library Bulletin: Words, 1960 March (Box 55, Folder 484-486)
      - The Journal of Medical Education: Medicine: The New Science and the Old Art, 1960 April (Box 55, Folder 484-486)
      - Political Research Organization and Design: Report of the Special Committee, 1960 May (Box 55, Folder 484-486)
      - Christianity and Crisis: Statistical Morality, 1960 August 8 (Box 55, Folder 484-486)
      - Dartmouth Conference: Issues of Man and His Environment, 1960 September 8-10 (Box 55, Folder 484-486)
      - Academy Reporter (Editorial): Science and Older Wisdom, 1960 October (Box 55, Folder 484-486)
      - Science: The Attractiveness of Dessert, 1960 November 25 (Box 55, Folder 484-486)
      - Science (Editorial): Disparagement of Statistical Evidence, 1960 December 23 (Box 55, Folder 484-486)
      - Think: Science: Why Every Man Should Take More Interest in Science, 1960 December (Box 55, Folder 484-486)
      - Alfred P. Sloan Foundation: A Great Age for Science, 1960 (Box 55, Folder 484-486)
      - AAAS Annual Meeting: The Moral Un-Neutrality of Science, 1960 (Box 55, Folder 484-486)
    - Works by Warren Weaver, 1961 (Box 55, Folder 487)